

CÉSAR CANDELA FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

PERSONAL INFO

Name: César Augusto Candela Vargas

Birth date: November 20th, 1975

Citizenship: Spain

Current location: Sofia, Bulgaria.

(+359) 88 456 7671

cesar@cssguy4hire.com

www.cssguy4hire.com

s cssguy4hire

ABOUT

Web Designer and **Front-end Developer**, **César Candela** has a wide experience designing and developing website Ul's, focusing mainly on **e-commerce web apps** thoroughly considering accessibility, usability and web standards concepts.

Devoted his work mainly to **Front-End web development** during the last decade, he has worked for different companies and international brands, gaining a good expertise over the **SFCC platform**, and **ReactJs** during the last five years.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES/SOFTWARE:

JavaScript
Jemandware/SFCC
Django
PHP

Others: Git/SVN, TypeScript, MySQL, MongoDB, Visual Studio Code, Sublime Text 3, Avocode, Zeplin.

DIGITAL EDITING SOFTWARE:

Others: Blender, 3ds Max, Flash Professional, DreamWeaver, Acrobat Pro, Premiere Pro.

PERSONAL SKILLS:

- Creativity/Imagination.
- Quick learning and adaptation.
- Team working.
- Good organization and Time management.
- Self-motivation.

- Good interpersonal and communication skills.
- Outstanding technical problems solver.
- · Good decisions making.
- Detail-oriented.

ROLFS

- Designing websites UI.
- Web pages coding and scripting (HTML5/CSS3/JS).
- Dynamic interfaces and visual effects creation/ scripting.
- · Content management.

- Search Engine Optimization (SEO).
- · Motion graphics.
- · Researching.
- · Testing.



EDUCATION

· Universidad Nacional de Colombia

(1993 - 1998)

Obtained degree: Graphic Designer

· 3ds Max official animation course, CICE

(2003)

WORK EXPERIENCE

• 2020 -

Company: The Stars Group

Gaming and online gambling company. Sofia, Bulgaria.

ReactJS Front-end Web Developer.

Responsible for the creation of new features for ReactJS web based applications, integrating business requirements, functionalities and UI designs. Integration with back-end based components using WebSockets. Writing of Unit and Integration tests, code reviewing and bug Fixing. Tracking of own progress of project issues with JIRA following Agile methodology.

• 2016 - 2019

Company: Accenture Bulgaria EOOD

Consulting and services company. Sofia, Bulgaria.

Senior Front-end Web Developer.

Responsible for the creation of different visual components, mirroring the designs specified UI functionality and requirements provided. Integration with the back-end based component on Demandware (SalesForce). Writing documentation, testing, code reviewing and bug Fixing. Tracking of own progress of project issues with JIRA following Scrum methodology.

• 2001 - 2016

Company: Proveedores de Presencia en Internet S.L.

Web Agency/E-commerce.

Madrid, Spain.

Front-end Web Developer and Senior Web Designer / UI Designer.

Responsible for graphic concept creation, UX/UI design and development, creation of technical and visual behaviors using JavaScript/JQuery and Action Script. Integration with back-end based components on Django and PHP. Checking for flaws on different platforms and operating systems, investigation and solution of technical problems.

• 1998 - 2000

Company: IPS Latino Net S.A./Red Colombia

Web Agency.

Bogotá, Colombia.

Web Designer / CMS maintenance.

Responsible for graphics conceptualization, UI design and content updating. Back-end integration based on ASP. Testing, investigation and solution of technical problems.

